## Clayton Seitz

### cwseitz@iu.edu cwseitz.github.io

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research focuses on reconstruction of super-resolution fluorescence microscopy images from single molecule localization microscopy (SMLM) time series. I design generative image models based on Markovian photoswitching of fluorescent molecules complemented by inference methods for super-resolution reconstruction. This involves a broad array of theoretical tools from physics, information theory, information geometry, and Bayesian statistics. Currently I am applying these models to study nucleosome organization and phase transitions of DNA-protein condensates during the immune response.

#### **EDUCATION**

Doctor of Philosopy, Physics

Purdue University, Indianapolis, IN, 2024

Thesis: Untitled

Master of Science, Biophysics

University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, 2021

Thesis: Stable cell assembly formation in excitatory-inhibitory neuronal networks

Bachelor of Science, Magna Cum Laude, Physics

Purdue University, Indianapolis, IN, 2019

Minor: Mathematics

Bachelor of Science, Magna Cum Laude, Informatics

Luddy School of Informatics, Computing, and Engineering, Indiana University Bloom-

ington, 2019

Concentration: Mathematics

# COMPUTER SKILLS

Languages & Software: Python, R, PyTorch, C, Git, LaTeX, Bash, Linux

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Research Assistant

2019-2021

Indiana University - Purdue University, Indianapolis, IN

- Develop an image processing software pipeline for high-throughput quantification of images in fluorescence microscopy
- Utilize high performance computing clusters for image segmentation, single particle tracking, and image registration

#### Undergraduate Research Assistant

2019-2020

Indiana University - Purdue University, Indianapolis, IN

- Utilize time-correlated single photon counting (TCSPC) to characterize the sub-Poissonian emission of organic quantum dots dispersed in a thin film of poly-methyl methacrylate (PMMA)
- $\bullet\,$  Design and utilize a 3-color imaging protocol to perform single-molecule imaging of mRNA transcripts in human epithelial kidney and osteosarcoma cells

Undergraduate Tutor

2018-2019

Indiana University - Purdue University, Indianapolis, IN

 Tutored undergraduate students in introductory physics courses covering classical mechanics, classical electromagnetism, circuit analysis, and modern physics

#### **AWARDS**

NIH Graduate Training Fellowship University of Chicago, Chicago, IL

2020

Travel Award and Lightning Talk Invitation Physical Sciences in Oncology - Minneapolis, MN 2019

Hudson and Holland Scholarship for Diversity and Inclusion

2013-2017

Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

Founders Scholar

2013-2017

Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

Cigital Scholarship

2016-2017

Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

PUBLICATIONS Maelle Locatelli<sup>†</sup>, Josh Lawrimore<sup>†</sup>, Hua Lin<sup>†</sup>, Sarvath Sanaullah, Clayton Seitz, Dave Segall, Paul Kefer, Salvador Moreno Naike, Benton Lietz, Rebecca Anderson, Julia Holmes, Chongli Yuan, George Holzwarth, Bloom Kerry, Jing Liu, Keith D Bonin, Pierre-Alexandre Vidi. DNA damage reduces heterogeneity and coherence of chromatin motions. PNAS. 2022

> Mengdi Zhang, Clayton Seitz, Garrick Chang, Fadil Iqbal, Hua Lin, and Jing Liu A guide for single-particle chromatin tracking in live cell nuclei. Cell Biology International. January 2022.

> Wenting Wu, Faroog Syed, Edward Simpson, Chih-Chun Lee, Jing Liu, Garrick Chang, Chuanpeng Dong, Clayton Seitz, Decio L. Eizirik, Raghavendra G. Mirmira, Yunlong Liu, Carmella Evans-Molina; Impact of Proinflammatory Cytokines on Alternative Splicing Patterns in Human Islets. Diabetes 1 January 2022; 71 (1): 116 - 127

> Clayton Seitz, Hua Lin, Keith Bonin, Pierre-Alexandre Vidi, and Jing Liu. Quantifying the spatiotemporal dynamics of dUTP labeled chromatin during the DNA damage response. Biophysical Society Annual Conference 2020

> Clayton Seitz, Hua Lin, Keith Bonin, Pierre-Alexandre Vidi, and Jing Liu. Quantifying the spatiotemporal dynamics of dUTP labeled chromatin during the DNA damage response. Physical Sciences in Oncology Annual Conference 2019

> Clayton Seitz, Andrew Reeser, Fangjia Li, and Jing Liu. Machine learning methods in image based transcriptomics at single molecule resolution. Biophysical Society Annual Conference 2019